

Enrico Liscio

PhD researcher

Personal Details

Date of birth 20/09/1993

City Rijswijk, the Netherlands

e-mail e.liscio@tudelft.nl

Personal Description

I truly believe that AI is an outstanding technology that can and must be used to help society progress. So that is what I set out to do: research and develop AI that can support us in better understanding each others. And I enjoy divulging it with videos for lay-people. Furthermore, as actor and former board member of an improvisational theatre association, I learned organizational and communication skills. Curiosity keeps me alive: learning something new brightens my days.

Working experience

2020-present PhD researcher, TU Delft, Topic: personal values estimation in value-sensitive deliberation. Use NLP techniques to estimate individuals' personal values from text while deliberating about a topic of discussion.

2017–2020 **Technical Lead & Deep learning developer**, Fizyr, Delft RoboValley, development and implementation of state-of-the-art deep learning vision algorithms to solve challenges in automation and logistics industry.

2016–2017 Graduate intern, Heemskerk Innovative Technology, Delft RoboValley, development of autonomous robotic grasping of objects in cluttered environments.

Education

2015–2017 Cum laude MSc, TU Delft, Final grade: 9/10. Systems and Control (with the Robotics Institute Excellence Scholarship)

2012–2015 **Cum laude BSc**, *Università degli studi di Bologna*, *Final grade: 110L/110*. Automation Engineering

Publications

- 2021 E. Liscio, M. van der Meer, L. C. Siebert, C. M. Jonker, Niek Mouter and P. K. Murukannaiah. 2021. Axies: Identifying and Evaluating Context-Specific Values. In AAMAS 2021, Online, IFAAMAS, 799-808.
- 2021 E. Liscio, M. van der Meer, C. M. Jonker and P. K. Murukannaiah. 2021. A Collaborative Platform for Identifying Context-Specific Values: Demonstration Track. In AAMAS 2021, Online, IFAAMAS, 1773-1775.

Awards

2015–2017 Excellence Scholarship, TU Delft Robotics scholarship, Robotics institute.

2011–2014 Excellence Scholarship, ENASARCO scholarship, ENASARCO.

Software proficiency

Python	••••	SpaCy	••••	SQLite	••••
C++	••••	Keras/TF	••••	ROS	••••
Linux	•••00	OpenCV	••••	L T _F X	••••

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English IELTS Certificate - 7.5/9 Conversationally fluent - C1 level

Dutch Delftse Methode Advanced 2

Independent user - B2 level

French Diplôme d'études en langue française (DELF) Can understand and speak - B1 level

Extra-Curricular Activities

2021-current **Volleyball**, *Inter Rijswijk*, player.

2015-current Improvisational theater, Delft Improv Group, improviser.

2016–2018 Board member, Delft Improv Group, chairman.

2016–2018 Volleyball/Basketball, D.S.V.V. Punch, player.

2016 **Coach**, *TU Delft*, coaching and leading new incoming students to the university in their summer welcoming Introduction Programme.